Guide to the Robert A. Hill Collection, 1890-2014 RL.10993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- African Volumes (AF), 1842-2010 and undated; 2; 37.5 Linear Feet 32 boxes
  - Annotated and Indexed Subjects, 1
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Journey of W.E.B. Dubois, 1924 May (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Keep Cool Quiz Book, 1927 Jun 11 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - King of Ethiopia Treaty with the U.S., 1904 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - L'Illustration, 1921 Mar 26 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - La Depeche Coloniale, 1921 Oct 22 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Lagos Weekly Record Black Star Line advertisement, 1921 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Les Continents - facsimile, 1924 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Liberian Proclamation, 1864 Mar 1 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Liberian Settlement, undated (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Liberian Technical Experts - facsimile, 1924 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Liberian Technician Recruitment, 1921 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Literacy Digest, The, 1922 Aug 19 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Loan Drive, $2 Million, 1921 Dec 17 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Malekebu, A Plea For Africa, undated (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - maps and facsimiles, African Series, 1994, 2000 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Marwanqana membership card, 1940 Jun 13 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Military Intelligence Division, 1921 Aug 29 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - miscellaneous, 1921-1926, 1928-1929, 1932 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World cartoons, Lost Nothin' in Africa, 1933 Jun 2 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World, advertisements, 1924 May 31 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World, Boers Bomb Hottentots, 1922 Jun 17 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World, front pages, 1918 Nov 30 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World, Plea for Democracy, 1919 Mar 1 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negro World, Possess this Land or Perish, 1927 Aug 13 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Negroes Open Fight on Garvey's Plan, 31-Jul (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - New York Herald, 1921 Aug (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - newspaper documents, African Series, 1915, 1921 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - newspaper documents, African Series, 1922 Mar 20 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - newspaper documents, African Series, 1921 Jun (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Pan-African Congress Resolutions, 1919 Feb 19-21 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - photos, African Series, undated; 2 folders (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - photos, African Series, 1928 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - photos, African Series, 1920 Jun 10 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Second Pan-African Congress, 1921 May (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Sierra Leone UNIA Meeting Advertisement, 1920 Jul 10 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Sons of Africa, 1937 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - South African Exclusion of Marcus Garvey, 1923 Jun 13 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - SWA, 1922 Jan 2 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Telegram de Marcus Garvey, undated (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Un Appel a la Race Negre, undated (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA Most Active Leaders, undated (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA application, 1922 Jan 2 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA Constitution and Book of Laws, 1918 Jul (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA application, 1920 Oct 20 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA Convention, 1922 Aug 1-22 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - UNIA Dance and Reception, 1922 Mar 29 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - Worker's Herald Advertisement for P & O, 1926 (Box AF27)
    - Facsimiles and Photos - World Magazine, 1921 Dec 4 (Box AF27)
    - Vol. VIII documents checked, undated (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII annotations to check, 1909-1923 (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1919 Jun (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1919 Aug (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1920 Jun (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1920 Aug (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII not Included, 1920 Aug (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1920 Sep (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII facsimiles and transcriptions, 1921 (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII chronology, 1995-1998 (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII corrections and additions, 1998 (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII research, 1999-2000 (Box AF28)
    - 1920 Aug 25-1919 Jan 15, 1921-1919; 85 folders (Box AF30)
    - African Series document counts, 2007 Feb 1 (Box AF31)
    - African Series photos and facsmiles, 1923, 1925, 1927 (Box AF31)
    - African Universal Church, Laura Kofey, 1925-1990 (Box AF31)
    - Annotations - correspondence and notes, 1988-1993 (Box AF31)
    - Annotations - completed, submitted, 1993-1994; 3 folders (Box AF31)
    - Annotation information, undated; 2 folders (Box AF31)
    - Annotation material, undated; 2 folders (Box AF31)
    - James Nimmo and Laura Adorkor Kofey, 1986 (Box AF31)
    - Photo research, 1979, 1983 (Box AF31)
    - Vol. X annotated page proofs, Part I, 1996 Jul; 3 folders (Box AF31)
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1920, 1932, 1935; 20 folders (Box AF32)
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1921-1939, 1966-1996, undated; 17 folders (Box AF33)
      Contents Include: Articles, chapters, and other writings on philanthropy, syncretism, religion, Yoruba Ethnogenesis, Simon Kimbangu, Stimela Jason Jingoes, Nigeria, Berlin West Africa Conference, Enlightenment, Age of Imperialism, Louisiana Colonization, Liberia, East African Christians, World War I, Church Missionary Society, Islam, Colonialism, Nationalism, British East Africa, and Cape Town Archives Repository. Materials may overlap with Research (RE).
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1943-1956; 17 folders (Box AF34)
      Contents Include: FBI records addressing the African Nationalist Pioneering Movement and the Afro-American National Infantry. Materials may overlap with Other Works (OW), Microfilm (MF), and Research (RE).
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1800-1917, 1918-2000, undated; 105 folders (Box AF35)
      Contents Include: Pan-Africanism, Germany, Edwardian Nationalism, Antiqua, St. Kitts, Colonization Movement, African Nationalism, Gold Coast, William Randolph Hearst, and Garveyism; newspaper articles on the war of the races, race war, and racial war; transcriptions; and keyword searches. Materials may overlap with Research (RE).
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1914-1927, 1938-2006, undated; 116 folders (Box AF36)
      Contents Include: John Stuart Young, Great Ethiopian Movement, Darker Races World Organization of 1827, William Wady Harris, Pan-Africanism, South Africans, Nigeria, Liberia, Yoruba, Nairobi, Zionism, Chief Sam, African Nationalism, Ethiopianism. Materials may overlap with Research (RE).
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1876-1930, 2001-2009, undated; 115 folders (Box AF37)
      Contents Include: African Colonization, French Africa, African Nationalism, Garveyism, World War I, Nationalism, Senegal Valley, Uganda, Faduma, British Africans, and Colonization Society. Materials may overlap with Research (RE).
    - Annotated and indexed documents, 1914-1937, 1918-2009, undated; 23 folders (Box AF38)
      Contents Include: Unsorted secondary source research for the eighth volume, keyword searches, primary source transcriptions, and research correspondence. Materials may overlap with Research (RE) and Project Administration (PA).
    - Annotated and Indexed Subjects, 1922-1924, 1965-1993, undated; 98 folders (Box AF39)
      Contents Include: Secondary source research for the eighth volume, organized alphabetically. Topics cover the Angolan Revolution, African Nationalism, Christianity in Africa, class relations, South Africa, colonialism, British policy, Liberia, conquest, and revolution and rebellion. Materials may overlap with Research (RE).
  - Drafts, Galleys and Proofs, 2
    The Drafts, Galleys and Proofs subseries is arranged by volume number and contains printed and annotated material for Volumes IX-X in various production stages. Printed front matter, introductions, and subject indexes are included in this subseries.
    - Annotated page proofs, undated (Box AF23)
    - Vol. I Binder 2 - Nick's version vetted and retired African Time and Orient Review, 1994 Apr; 3 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. I-III catalog, jacket copy, introduction, 1994 (Box AF23)
    - Vol. II miscellaneous annotated page proofs, undated; 2 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. II and III introductions, undated (Box AF23)
    - Vol. IV annotated draft, undated; 4 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. VI acknowledgments, 1985-1988; 3 folders (Box AF23)
    - All Volumes - History of the Edition, undated (Box AF23)
    - Vol. X biographical appendix, annotated, undated (Box AF23)
    - Essays on Garveyism by contributing editors, undated; 2 folders (Box AF23)
    - Africa for the Africans 1917-1945 - annotated pageproofs (Box AF23)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, 1913-1921; 3 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, Barbor's binder, 1992; 4 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. VIII and X drafts of acknowledgments, 1997 (Box AF23)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs - 2000 Edition, 3 folders (Box AF23)
    - Vol. IX Africa for the Africans - annotated page proofs Part 1, 1921-1922; 3 folders (Box AF24)
      pg xi-322
    - Vol. IX Africa for the Africans - annotated page proofs Part 2, 1921-1922; 3 folders (Box AF24)
      pg 323-740
    - Vol. IX annotated page proofs, 1920-1922, 1993-1994; 17 folders (Box AF24)
      pg 1-1991
    - Vol. IX Binder 2, Barbara's binder, July '92 version, 1992; 3 folders (Box AF25)
      pg 621-1199
    - Vol. IX annotated page proofs - Ricky's version, 1994 Feb-Mar; 10 folders (Box AF25)
      pg 200-2191
    - Vol. IX annotated page proofs, 1921, 1923-1925, undated; 11 folders (Box AF25)
      pg 1-392
    - Vol. IX annotated page proofs, 1923-1925; 4 folders (Box AF25)
      pg 1221-1549
    - Vol. X annotated page proofs, 1923-1925; 10 folders (Box AF26)
      pg i-1508
    - Vol. X annotated drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box AF26)
      pg 1550-1880
    - Vol. X biographical appendix - annotated, undated (Box AF26)
    - Vol. X French documents, 1992 Jul (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XI biographical appendix, 1992 Mar; 2 folders (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XI notes, integrated, 1990 (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XI image copies, 2005-2006 (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XI research, 2006 (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XIII biographical appendix - master copy, undated; 2 folders (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XIII binder number 1, Kent's version, 1992 Jul; 3 folders (Box AF26)
    - Vol. XII and Vol. XIII transcription list, undated (Box AF26)
    - Vol. IX Kent edition, continued, 1990-1993 (Box AF26)
    - Unknown Volume - annotated page proof, undated (Box AF26)
    - Unknown Volume - index, undated (Box AF26)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, undated; 8 folders (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs lxxxi-653, undated; 6 folders (Box AF28)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, Binder 1, 1996 Jun; 3 folders (Box AF29)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, Binder 2, 1996 Jun; 3 folders (Box AF29)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, 2000 (Box AF29)
    - Vol. VIII annotated page proofs, 2000 edition, 3 folders (Box AF29)
    - Vol. VIII volumes and drafts photo facsimiles, 2000 (Box AF29)
    - Annotated proofs, 1985, undated; 4 folders (Box AF32)
    - Vol. VIII transciptions, page proofs, 2010, undated; 2 folders (Box AF32)
    - Contibutor essays, 1992-1993, undated; 2 folders (Box AF32)
  - Annotated Subjects, 12 boxes
    - Abantu Batho through Barrett, Schism and Renewal in Africa, 1895, 1901-1995, undated; 58 folders (Box AF40)
      Contents include: Abantu Batho; Abilene Christian University Conference; Adas, Peasant Protest in Southeast Asia
    - Black Star Line through James Bryce, 1857-1993, undated; 97 folders (Box AF41)
      Contents include: Black Star Line; Frederick Douglass papers; R.J.M. Blackett; Britain, Sahara, and Western Sudan; Victorianism and Race; Mid-Victorian Imperialism; Bolshevism; WWI; Black Miners' Strike; Dutch and Black Africans; British Imperialism; Central Africa; Braide, Garrack; Christian Awakening in West Africa; Missionaries in Niger Delta; Africans in England; Braithwaite, William S.; Railways in North Africa; Resistance in Kenya; Heart of Darkness; Resistance in Kenya; Ethnicity and Nationalism; Language, Religion, and Politics in North India; Muslims of South Asia; Race Relations in Colonial Trinidad; John Jacob Thomas; Nationalism and the State; Russwurm, John B.; The Crusader; Anatomy of Revolution; Britain and the British Academy; British East Africa; Liberia; Negroes and the American Revolution; Sudanese Mahdiya; Pan-Islamism; National Identity in Early-African American Colonization; Roman and British Empire; Studies in History and Jurisprudence; Mau Mau; S. African Peasantry; Bunyoro; Moroccan Resistance; Moroccan Resistance to French Colonialism; Imperial Architects; Burundi; Pan-Islam; and Luanda Under Belgian Rule.
    - Ghana through Hopkins, 1904-1995, undated; 103 folders (Box AF42)
      Contents include: Ghana; Afrikaner Nationalism; Le Tirailleur Senegalais; Gold Coast, Seditious Offences; Gold Coast Leader articles; The Egyptian Nationalist Party; Race Relations in the Rhodesias and Nysaland; The Two Nations; Caribbean Personnel in Gold Coast Administration 1900-1911; Publishing History of Olaudah Equiano; The Anglo-French Conquest of Togo, 1914; South African Blacks and WWI; Ernest Gellner Obituary; Selected Subaltern Studies; Guinea; Archdeacon Crowther and the Delta Pastorate; Niger Languages; Imperialism and Labour; Free Villages of Jamaica; Henry Morton Stanley; American Interest in the Exploration of the Dark Continent; Handbook for East Africa, Uganda and Zanzibar; Liberia, Price of Independence; Transformation of Free Town; Roots of Ethnicity; Prophet William Wade Harris; Fitzherbert Headley; Ulysses' Sail; Nationalism; Italian Imperialism; The Formation of an Industrial Proletariat in Southern Africa; Making Noise: Marcus Garvey Dada, August 1922; Kenya and Uganda Railway; Zion on the Zambezi; Lumpa Church; All African Convention; Imperium et Libertas; Blundering and Plundering; The Lagos Strike of 1897; Nigerian Cocoa Farming Industry; and Wittgenstein, Interpretation and Psychoanalysis.
    - Stock through Van Vuuren, 1899-1996, undated; 94 folders (Box AF43)
      Contents include: Church Missionary Society; The Peasant Armed; Scramble for Africa; Sudan; African Congress; African History; Racial Difference in Britain; Tagoe, Enoch; Cape Afrikaner Ethnic Consciousness; Tamir, Yael; Nyasaland; Tanzania; Colonial Rule in West Africa; African Telegraph Articles; Temperley, Howard; Temu, Arnold; Russia and Balkan Influence; Therborn; Bongo Riots in Ghana; Caribbean-American Associations; Thomas, H.B.; Thompson, Leonard; African Native Land Settlement; Thornton, A.P.; Kenya Colony; Kikuyu Association; Kenya Historical Biographies; Pan-African Politicians in East Africa; Knapp and William Jenkins Correspondence; Thuku, Harry; Tibebu, Teshale; Times of London; Tinker, Hugh; The German Colonies; Togo; Black Social Theory in the Gilded Age; Islamic Political Propaganda in Nigeria; Toney, Joyce; Zik's story; Chapman, Malcolm; McDonald, Maryon; Tonkin, Elizabeth; Touraine, Alain; Peasantry in Dominica; Kakungulu and the Creation of Uganda; Uganda Medals and Decorations; Nationalism in the Gold Coast; Uganda; Education in Uganda; Delany, Martin; Native Commissioner Reports; Footsoldiers of UNIA; Aba Riots or Igbo Women's War; Racism in Europe; 1912 Wankie Colliery Strike; Labour Migration and Tonga Society; Lakeside Tonga of Nyasaland; Pressure Groups in Malawi; Women Against Apartheid; and The War and Its Aftermath.
    - Okonkwo, Rina through Puse, Mohammed Ali, 1857-1990, undated; 103 folders (Box AF44)
      Contents include: 1926 Railway Strike; Renaissance Man of Africa; Pallinder, Agneta; Cole, Abayomi; Africa and the International Economy; Africa Mythology; Cocoa Production; African Churches in Yoruba; African Politics; African Conversion; African Influence on French Railroad Production; Africanism; Nigerian Cocoa; Europeans and Ancestors; French West Africa; African Resistance to the Atlantic Slave Trade in West Africa; Buxton, Sir Thomas Fowell; African American Myth; African Times and Orient Review; African Synthesis; Africa's Northern Great Lakes Region; Fyfe, Christopher; Ajayi, J.F.A.; Agbebi, Mojola; Ancestors as Elders in Africa; Temperley, Howard; Anti-slavery and Aborigines Protection Society; Jenkins, Roy; Atlantic Slave Trade; Azikiwe, Nnamdi; Wyse, H.C.; The 1911 Universal Races Congress; Baroque; The Battle of Abeokuta; Belgian Congo; The Berlin Conference and the Expansion of Europe; The Bible and the Plough; Black Europeans and White Africans; Black Mischief; Braidwood, Stephen J.; The Black Republic; Bowen, Thomas Jefferson; Tilly, Charles; Lynn, Martin; Anti-slavery Reporters; Jenkins, Roy; The Atlantic Slave Trade; Wyse, H.C.; British Commerce as Anti-Slavery Device; Colley, Linda; Building an Anti-slavery Wall; The Cabo Verde Archipelago-Western African Nexus; Nigeria; The Evangelical Impact on the Victorians; Campbell, Robert; Delany, Martin; Captive Kings British Anti-Slavery literature; Quinn, Frederick; Christian Life in the Age of Bishop Crowther; African Nationalism; Colonial Cameroon; Ibadan; Berry, Cocoa; Colonial African History; Christianity and Civilization; Spirit Cults in Uganda; Colonial Economy of the Former French, Belgian, and Portuguese Zones; Colonialism in Africa; Colonial rule in tropical Africa; Commerce and Christianity; Commerce and Empire; Creoles; Urban Efik and Ibo in Nigeria; The Concept of Elites; Congo Cosmology; Theatre in Lagos; Crops and Wealth in Uganda; Government in the Lower Congo; Da Costa; Dakar Railway Network; Moses da Rocha; Davies, H.O.; Johnson, J.W.; McWilliam, H.O.A.; African Medical Officers; Cameroon; and Puse, Mohammed Ali.
    - Earlier Histography of Colonial Africa through Ofasu-Appiah, 1842-1996, undated; 117 folders (Box AF45)
      Contents include: Earlier Historiography of Colonial Africa; Farias and Barber; Easmon; Economic Aspects of Political Movements in Nigeria and the Golf Coast; Ekiti Parapo; Economic Basis of Imperialism; Economic Model of Colonialism; Educated Elite in the Nigerian Society; Educated Native; Efik Political Agents of Old Calabar; Efik Traders of Old Calabar; The Egba; Johnson, George William; Egypt in America; Empire and Authority; Empire and Social Engineering; Empire and the English Character; Miers, Suzanne; Roberts, Richard; England's Mission; Casely, Hayford; Ethnic Nationalism; European and Creole Influence in the Hinterland of Sierra Leone; European Beginnings in West Africa; Evangelical Revival; Exiled African; Extinction of the Slave Trade; Fall of the Oyo Empire; Senegal; Brown, Robert T.; Herskovits; Sierra Leone emigrants; Abeokuta; Hausa Kola Traders in the Nineteenth Century; the Fouta-Djalon Chieftaincy; Fowell Buxton; Haller, Foxe; Ijagbemi, E.A.; Berque, Jacques; Devisch, Rene; Greenland; Weinstein, Gabon; Gandhi's Rise to Power; Aristocracy, Balkan Wars; Lectures, Editorials by and about Garvey; English Nationalism; History of Africa; Stephens, George; Gold Coast; Articles About Peoples of the Gold Coast; Ibadan; The Government of Subject Races; Articles by Hall, Stuart; Myth; Articles on the Gold Coast by Casely-Hayford, J.E.; African Civilization Society; Henry Venn and the Policy of Development; Mau; History of Christianity in Africa; History of West Africa; The Nation and Empire; African Nationalism; Cairns, H. Alan; Ayandale, E.A.; Hunkanrin, Louis; Ibo; Self-Governing Church; Morrill, W.T.; Hopkins, A.G.; Imperial Conference in 1911; Imperial Federation League; Imperialism and Popular Culture; The Imperialism of Free Trade; The Crusader; Independency and Prophetism; Nineteenth-Century Lagos; Ireland for the Irish; Kamara, John; African Mercantile Entrepreneurship in the Gold Coast; Clarkson, John and the Sierra Leone Company; Ofasu-Appiah; and Hayford, Joseph Ephraim Casely.
    - Kalibala, Ernest through Morton-Williams, Peter, 1861-1995, undated; 82 folders (Box AF46)
      Contents include: Kalibala, Ernest; Kimbangu, Martin; Kimbangu, Simon; Kimbanguist Movement; King Akwa of Cameroon; Murphy, Cullen; Kola Trade and Upper Guinea Coast; Senegambia; The Krio of Sierra Leone; Sierra Leone Krios; Krio Political biography; Nkrumah, Kwame; Ackan-Watson; Labor Protest Activity in Sierra Leone; Colonial Freetown; Lagos Weekly Record; Lagos Weekly Record; Lagos Youth League; Lancashire and the American Civil War; Late-Victorian Sexual Respectability; Lebaudy, Jacques; Yorubaland; Liberia and Ethiopia; Liberia and the UNIA; Articles About Liberia; Ellis, George W.; Jalland, Patricia; Liberian Colonization; Abdullah, Ibrahim; British Imperialism; British West African Policy; Austen, Ralph; Mail and Western Sudan; Making Europes; Markets in Iboland; Markets in Yorubaland; Delany, Martin R.; Margai, Sir Albert; Kingsley, Mary; Protest in Eighteenth-Century Afro-English Writing; Sierra Leonians in London; Hayford, Casely; Cameroon Hinterland; Nineteenth Century Yoruba Country: The Ibadan Empire; Militarism in Britain Before the Great War; Missionary Education in Colonial Africa; Missionary Enterprise and Rivalry in Igboland; Missionary Secretariat of Henry Venn; Suppression of the Transatlantic Slave Trade; Cole, Patrick; Tanganyika; Mojola and Adeotan Agbebi; Turner; Mountebank; Jenkins, Roy; Nairobi Union of Baganda Workers; National Congress of British West Africa; Nationalism and New States in Africa; Akyem Abuakwa; the Native Clerk in Colonial West Africa; Complaints Against British Merchants; The Navy and the Slave Trade; The New Liberalism; Nigeria; Nigerian Hinterland and the African Diaspora; Nigerian Newspaper Editors; Nigerian Nationalism; Nineteenth-Century Yorubaland; Oliver, Lord; The Nigerian Press and the Great War; Obisesan, Chief Akin Pelu; Delany, Martin Robison; Pageantry and politics; Postmodernism; Origins of West African Nationalism; Letters from Black Settlers in Africa; Blackburn, Robin; and Oyo Yoruba and the Atlantic Trade.
    - Paul Panda Farnana M'Fumu through The Yoruba-Speaking People of Nigeria, 1856-1996, undated; 114 folders (Box AF47)